# Warapong Pheumjai

Phone 088-676-4133
Email warapong.pj@gmail.com
LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/warapong-pheumjai-3894b8205
GitHub https://github.com/warapong-pj

#### **Profile**

I have experienced many years in IT role. I start with IT helpdesk, my responsible is take care end user to fix problem that relate computer. I work in this role about 3 years and then I give a chance promote to System Administrator, in this role my responsible is maintain service that run on OS(Windows and Linux) like Activity Directory, DNS, DHCP, File Share and Web Server service and manage VM(VMware and Hyper-V). Also, I have chance maintain network and firewall device. After I work in System Administrator about 2 years, I hear about DevOps culture, and I interest this. which I have research responsible about role, And I give change again. My responsible for this role is provide CI/CD pipeline for deploy application on cloud environment(AWS and Azure). I still have implemented monitoring tools, also include integrate monitoring tools and implement many tools to improve workload with our application. Currently I still work on this role, I like research tools for continue to improve my job and share new technology with my team.

## **Experience**

## DEVOPS ENGINEER | AIA | APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

- Develop and maintain CI/CD pipeline
- Implement, integrate and maintain monitoring tools(Prometheus & Grafana), logging tools(ELK stack)
- Create and maintain resource cloud environment(Azure)
- Raise ticket to vendor for support maintain/deploy cloud components on Azure
- Support develop team to investigate issue
- Generate report and fix security issue(If security is relate DevOps team like vulnerability assessment in OS/Incorrect configuration on Cloud environment)
- Cloud costs optimize(Decommission unuse components)

## **DEVOPS ENGINEER | AI AND ROBOTICS VENTURES | MARCH 2022 - MARCH 2023**

- Create and maintain Helm/Kustomize to use to deploy application
- Provide CI/CD pipeline to build and deploy application to EKS and Lambda(GitLab CI)
- Provide and manage resource on cloud environment by Terraform(AWS)
- Implement and integrate monitoring(Prometheus & Grafana), logging(Promtail & Loki) and tracing(Jaeger & OpenSearch) to application
- Investigate issue/suggest tools to improve performance application
- Cloud costs optimize(Right sizing instance and schedule start/stop workload on Non-Production)
- Integrate hardware with software from develop team like integrate OpenCV with NVIDIA CUDA, running machine learning on Kubernetes with EC2 GPU instance.

- Implement GitOps tools to sync configuration between Git server and EKS cluster(Argo CD & GitLab)
- Apply SAST and DAST tools to scan vulnerability assessment on application

#### **DEVOPS ENGINEER | AMITY | NOVEMBER 2021 - FEBURARY 2022**

- Deploy application by use GitOps concept to EKS(Argo CD)
- Provide and manage resource by use Infrastructure as a Code on AWS(Pulumi)
- Implement Argo Rollouts to apply deployment strategy
- Investigate and solve problem/issue that happen from system/application
- Develop and maintain existing pipeline to build and deploy application(Circle CI)
- Cloud costs optimize(Clean up unuse resource)

## DEVOPS ENGINEER | THAI CREDIT RETAIL BANK PUBLIC COMPANY LIMITED | MAY 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

- POC integrate component on AWS(Create CI/CD tools and AWS SAM template)
- Develop CI/CD pipeline to help developer build and deploy application on serverless architecture
- Convert from existing AWS infrastructure to infrastructure as a code by AWS CloudFormation
- Help support/dev team to investigate/resolve application issue
- Apply DevOps and Agile culture to improve performance team

#### **DEVOPS ENGINEER | ASCEND GROUP | MARCH 2020 - MAY 2021**

- Deploy application in production environment(Continuous Delivery concept)
- Integrate monitoring, logging and tracing tools with infrastructure and application
- Manage resource and provide infrastructure both on cloud(AWS) and on-premise(VMware)
- Transform application technology from hosted to container technology
- Develop CI/CD pipeline for Kubernetes
- Communicate with Dev team to planning tasks on sprint planning
- Research technology to reduce team workload

#### SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR | KAIDEE | NOVEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

- Design, migrate and implement services to new hardware
- Manage user and deploy permission to cloud services
- Monitor and resolve problem that occurred from service
- Responsible to manage asset in company

#### SYSTEM ENGINEER | BESTSERVE CONSULTING | APRIL 2019 - OCTOBER 2020

- Investigate, resolve problem that was informed by NOC Team
- Create and perform follow work plan or report as by customer request
- Contact vender to replace hardware in case hardware failed or when need more information about product
- Prepare OS and install basic software

### SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR | BARAWINDSOR AND KRATOS GROUP | SEPTEMBER 2014 -**MARCH 2019**

- Implement, manage and upgrade hypervisor(VMware) for deploy virtual machine, integrate with another services
- Install and manage by users or customer request for example Domain Controller, DNS, DHCP, File Sharing, Mail Server, Web Server
- Monitor, resolve problem that occurred with servers or services
- Design and test solution to apply new project
- Coordinator service providers or system integration to ask information about products and services

#### **Education**

## COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEM | AUGUST 2014 | RAJAMANGALA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY KRUNGTHEP, BANGKOK

#### **Skills & Abilities**

- Cloud Computing(AWS and Azure)
- · Infrastructure as a Code(Terraform, Pulimi and Cloud Formation)
- Container Technology(Docker and Kubernetes)
- · Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery(Jenkins, GitLab and GitHub)
- Configuration Management(Ansible)
- · Monitoring Tools(Grafana, CloudWatch and Azure Monitor)
- Logging Tools(ELK stack, OpenSearch and Promtail)
- · Tracing Tools(Jaeger, OpenTelemetry and Dynatrace) · Virtual Machine(VMware and Hyper-V)
- · Secret Management(Hashicorp Vault, AWS Secret Manager and Azure Key Vault)
- DevSecOps(Snyk, Checkov, Kyverno)

- · GitOps(Argo CD) and Deployment Strategies (Argo Rollouts)
- Internal Developer Platform(Backstage)
- Chaos Engineer(Chaos Mesh)
- · Extract, Transform and Load(Apache Airflow and Azure Datafactory)
- Capture Data Change(Kafka Connector)
- Load Testing(Grafana k6)
- · Operating System(Windows, Linux and MacOS)
- · Computer Networking(VLAN, Spanning Tree, Aggregate Link and Routing)